Inventory of the Carter Family Papers 1667-1862
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- People Files, 1667-1862. (Folder 1-102)
  - Carter, (Robert W.) 1792-1861; 1803-1862, n.d. (Folder 20-101)
    - Letters, 1803-1861. (Folder 20-50)
      - Letters, 1837-1838., 36 items. (Folder 26)
        - John Tayloe Lomax, at Fredericksburg, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond City, 13 Jan 1838., 1 item. (Folder 26)
        - William H. Tayloe, at Mount Airy, [Richmond County], to Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 31 Jan 1838., 1 item. (Folder 26)
        - Joseph Palmer, at Farnham, [Richmond County], Virginia, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond City, 1 Feb 1838., 1 item. (Folder 26)
        - J[oseph] Palmer, at Woodland, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond City, 1 March 1838., 1 item. (Folder 26)
        - [Robert W. Carter], at Richmond, to William H. Roane, [at Washington], 10 March 1838., 1 item. (Folder 26)
        - Murray Forbes, at Falmouth, [Stafford County], to Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, 28 March 1838., 1 item. (Folder 26)
        - John Taliaferro, at Washington, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 29 March 1838., 1 item. (Folder 26)
        - D. Green, William Brooke, Jr., and John M. O'Bannon, at Falmouth, [Stafford County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond Court House, Virginia, 12 April 1838., 1 item. (Folder 26)
        - J. Chowning, at Lancaster Court House, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond Court House, 26 April 1838., 1 item. (Folder 26)
        - Lemuel L. Woollard, Northumberland County, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Fredericksburg, Virginia, 4 Aug 1838., 1 item. (Folder 26)
        - Virginia Tayloe, at Washington, to Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, Virginia, 5 Dec 1838., 1 item. (Folder 26)
          Virginia Tayloe is a sister of RWC.
      - Letters, 1839., 24 items. (Folder 27)
        - Lemuel L. Woollard to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 1 Jan 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - Carter Mitchell, at Wilna, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 2 Jan 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - M. B. Carter, per M. C., at Shooters Hill, [King George County], to Col. Robert Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 3 Jan 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
          Re: Fire at RWC's house
        - Aug[ustin] Neale, at Shandy Hall, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 6 Jan 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
          Enclosure: One Caaount.
        - Benjamin Ogle Tayloe, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 9 Jan 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - John Tayloe Lomax, Jr., at Demopolis, Ala., to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 11 Jan 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - Benjamin Ogle Tayloe, at Was[hington], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 14 Jan 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - Elizabeth [Carter] to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 20 Jan 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
          Elizabeth Carter is Col. Robert W. Carter's daughter.
        - Benjamin Ogle Tayloe, at Was[hington], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 31 Jan 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - Virginia Tayloe, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 1 Feb 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - Thomas D. Mutter, at Philadelphia, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 28 Feb 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - W. Y. Sturman, at Warsaw, [Richmond County], to R. W. Carter, 9 March 1839., 1 item. Mutilated. (Folder 27)
        - Rebecca Dulaney to Col. [Robert] W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 11 April 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
          Rebecca Dulaney is Col. [Robert] W. Carter's niece.
        - Virginia Tayloe, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, Virginia, 27 April 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - James M. Stiff, at Richmond Courthouse, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, 18 June 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - J. A. Carter, at Upperville, [Fauquier County], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Warsaw, Virginia, 28 June 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - Benjamin Ogle Tayloe, at Washington, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Virginia, 12 July 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - William Hindman, at Baltimore, to Robert W. Carter, at Warrenton Springs, Virginia, 7 Sept 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - Virginia [Tayloe], at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, Virginia, 2 Oct 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - Benjamin Story, at New Orleans, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 8 Nov 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - J. A. Carter, at Milan, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Virginia, 13 Nov 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - Two letters written on the same page, Elizabeth Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, Virginia, and Virginia [Tayloe] to Robert W. Carter, 20 Dec 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - W. B. Barton, at Fredericksburg, to Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, Virginia, 1839., 1 item. (Folder 27)
        - R. W. C[arter] to B. O. Tayloe, 1839., 1 item. Copy. (Folder 27)
      - Letters, 1840., 36 items. (Folder 28)
        - Dr. V. Y. Conway, at Stafford Court House, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 16 Jan 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - Benjamin Story, at New Orleans, to Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 18 Jan. 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - William M. McCarty; at Cedar Grove, [Fairfax County], to Col. Robert Carter, at Richmond, 19 Jan 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - G. Mason, at Hollin Hall, Virginia, near Alexandria, D. C., to Col. Robert Carter, at Richmond, 24 Jan 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
          Re: Bill regarding the "discipline of our slaves on this vexed Border" (D. C.).
        - C. Carter Lee, at Front Run Furnace, near Wardensville, Hardy County, to Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 31 Jan 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
          Re: Annexation of Hardy Co.
        - W. Y. Sturman, at Warsaw, to Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 10 Feb 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - T. B. Barton, at Fredericksburg, to R. W. Carter, at Richmond, 18 Feb 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - R. W. C[arter], at Richmond, to [T. B ] Barton, 18 Feb 1840., 1 item. [Copy]. (Folder 28)
        - John W. Nash, [at Richmond], to Col. Robert W. Carter, [at Richmond], 23 Feb 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - T. B. Barton, at Fredericksburg, to Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, 24 Feb 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - Virginia [Tayloe], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 4 March 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - John Taliaferro, at Washington, to Col. R. W. Carter, 10 March 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - B. W. Leigh to Robert W. Carter, [at Richmond], 14 March 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - D. C. Randolph, at Richmond, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond Court House, 13 April 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - R. E. Scott, at Warrenton, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, Virginia, 15 April 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - Robert B[?] Corbin, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, 16 April 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - E. B. Bentley, agent for Manchester C[otton] and W[ool] Manufacturing Company, at Richmond, to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 4 May 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - B. Peyton, at New Orleans, to Robert W. Carter, near Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 4 May 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - R. W. C[arter] to J. Smith, 7 May 1840., 1 item. [Copy]. (Folder 28)
        - J. M. Smith, at Mantua, [Northumberland County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, 16 May 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - L.L. Woollard to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, 8 June 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - Henley & Lomax, at Demopolis, [Alabama], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 14 June 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - John D. Corbin, at Richmond, to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 30 June 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - John S. Corbin, at Richmond, to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, 22 July 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - E. B. Bentley, at Richmond, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond, Virginia, 10 Aug 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - John S. Corbin, at Richmond, to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 18 Aug 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
          Note: Statements by a sporting court in regard to sweepstakes at Fairfield appear on same sheet.
        - William H. Tayloe, at Washington, to Robert W. Carter, at Lee's Springs, Fauquier County, Virginia, 28 Aug 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - [R. W. Carter to John S. Corbin, Sept 1840]., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - Two letters written on the same page, M. L. Eustace, at Wingville, to [Robert W. Carter], and W. C. Eustace to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw, Virginia, 23 Oct 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - V. Y. Conway, at Stafford Court House, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 31 Oct 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - Carter Mitchell, at Tappahannock, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 4 Dec 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - Auf[ustin] Neale, at Shandy Hall, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Richmond, 6 Dec 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
          Re: Divorce Proceedings.
        - Two letters written on the same page, Elizabeth L. Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, and Ann Tayloe to Col. Robert W. Carter, 9 Dec 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - Two letters written on the same page, Elizabeth Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, and [Anne Tayloe?] to Robert W. Carter. 26 Dec 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - F. Lemoine, at Warsaw, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 29 Dec 1840., 1 item. (Folder 28)
        - [John Armistead Carter], at Upperville, [Fauquier County], to Robert [Carter], 30 Dec 1840., 1 item. Incomplete. (Folder 28)
      - Letters, 1841., 36 items. (Folder 29)
        - C. Hughes Armistead, at Fredericksburg, Virginia, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 5 Jan 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Elizabeth L. Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 7 Jan 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - F. Lemoine, at Marske, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 8 Jan 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - M. B. Carter, at Sluters Hill, to Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 9 Jan 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Lucy Tomlin, at Wingville, to Col. Robert W. Carter, Richmond County, Virginia, 14 Jan 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Addison Hall, at Kilmarnock, [Lancaster County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, 18 Jan 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Two letters written on the same page, Elizabeth L. Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, and [Anne Tayloe] to Col. Robert W. Carter, 29 Jan 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - J. A. Carter to Col. Robert [W. Carter], 2 Feb 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - E. L. C[arter], at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 20 Feb 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - William A. Brockenbrough, at Warsaw, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 22 Feb 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Law[rence] Washington, at Blenheim, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, 4 March 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Elizabeth Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 14 March 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - J. A Parker, at Tappahannock, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 25 March 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Elizabeth Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw, Virginia, 29 March 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
          Note: Describes inauguration parade of President W. H. Harrison.
        - William A. Brockenbrough, at Warsaw, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 6 April 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - William N. Ward, at [The] Rectory, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 7 April 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - John L. Marye, at Fredericksburg, to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, 19 April 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - M. B. Carter to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Virginia, 20 April 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Samuel N. Edwards, at Leesburg, [Loundoun County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 21 April 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Elizabeth Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 11 June 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - M. B. Carter, to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 22 June 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - William A. Brockenbrough, at Warsaw, to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, at Sabine Hall, 24 June 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Elizabeth Landon Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 12 Aug 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
          Elizabeth Landon Carter is Col. Robert W. Carter's daughter.
        - Edward T. Tayloe, at Powhatan Hill, [King George County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 12 Aug 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - F. M. B. Roy, at Rose Hill, [Middlesex County], to Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw, Richmond County, 19 Aug 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Elizabeth Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warrington Springs, Fauquier County, Virginia, 12 Sept 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - E. J. Cooper, at Baltimore, to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, at Sabine Hall, 16 Sept 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Elizabeth Landon Carter, at Washington, to Col. R. W. Carter, near Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 2 Oct 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - William C. Eustace, at Wingville, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 4 Nov 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - E. Virginia Lomax, at Watertown Arsenal, [Watertown, Mass.], to Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, Virginia, 17 Nov 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Elizabeth L. Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 18 Nov 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Robert Mayo, Jr., at Auburn, [Mathews County], to Col. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 23 Nov 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Anne Tayloe to Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 29 Nov 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
          Postmarked Washington.
        - E. J. Cooper, at Baltimore, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Virginia, 1 Dec 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - W. A. Franklin, at Durrettsville, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Virginia, 15 Dec 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
        - Elizabeth L. Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 16 Dec 1841., 1 item. (Folder 29)
      - Letters, 1842., 31 items. (Folder 30)
        - Elizabeth Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 9 Jan 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Thomas C. Scott, at Falmouth, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 31 Jan 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
          Re: Sale of RWC's cotton stock.
        - Aug[ustin] Neale, at Shandy Hall, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richm[ond], 1 Feb 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - R. W. C[arter], at Richmond, to J. M. Bates, 3 Feb 1842., 1 item. [Copy]. (Folder 30)
        - B. W. Leigh, at Richmond, to R. W. Carter, [at Richmond], 7 Feb 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Elizabeth Landon Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 18 Feb 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Henley & Lomax, at Demopolis, [Alabama], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 24 Feb 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - John S. Corbin, at Powhatan House, [Richmond], to Col. R. W. Carter, [at Richmond], 28 Feb 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Elizabeth Landon Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 5 March 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Murray Forbes, at Falmouth, to Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, 7 March 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - John S. Corbin, at Old Church, Hanover County, to Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, Virginia, 31 March 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Elizabeth Landon Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 3 May 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - John S. Corbin, at Old Church [Hanover County], to Robert W. Carter, at Richmond Court House, Virginia, 12 May 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - S. A. M. Leland, Northumberland County, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 12 May 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Elizabeth Landon Carter, at Washington, to Col. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, Virginia, 17 May 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - W. R. Johnson, at Petersburg, to Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, Virginia, 1 July 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Corbin Braxton, at Chericoke, [King William County], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Richmond Court House, Virginia, 5 July 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
          Note: This letter concerns the newly-invented McCormick Reaper.
        - Elizabeth Landon Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 10 Aug 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - W. R. Johnson, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, Richmond County, Virginia, 7 Oct 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
          2 Enclosures: A sheet giving speed records of certain horses, 1802-1823, and a newspaper clipping concerning the Mount Vernon Races, 1842.
        - Elizabeth Landon Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, near Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 8 Oct 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Edward T. Tayloe, at Powhatan Hill, [King George County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 13 Oct 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - M. L. Brasham, [at Rose Hill], to Col. R. W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, 14 Oct 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Elizabeth Landon Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, near Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 29 Oct 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - F. M. B. Roy, at Rose Hill, [Middlesex County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 24 Nov 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Thomas Oldham to Col. Robert W. Carter, near Warsaw, Virginia, 26 Nov 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Elizabeth Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 9 Dec 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - William H. Hill, at Sabine Hall, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 12 Dec 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Mary B. Carter, at Alexandria, to Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 15 Dec 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - Thomas C. Braxton, at Fredericksburg, to Col. Robert Carter, Richmond County, 20 Dec 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
        - J. W. Gresham to Col. R. W. Carter, at Richmond Court House, Virginia, 26 Dec 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
          Postmarked Lancaster Court House.
        - Elizabeth Land[on Carter], at Washington, to Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 29 Dec 1842., 1 item. (Folder 30)
      - Letters, 1843-1844., 64 items. (Folder 31)
        - F. W. Pendleton, at Farnham, [Richmond County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 10 Jan 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - John S. Corbin to Col. [Robert W.] Carter, [at Richmond], 11 Jan 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - Thomas C. Braxton, at Farnham Church, [Richmond County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 12 Jan 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - Thomas Oldham, Richmond County, Virginia, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 12 Jan 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - C. Braxton, at Chericoke, [King William County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 13 Jan 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - William W. Forester to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 14 Jan 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
          Postmarked Farnham, Virginia
        - William H. Hill, at Sabine Hall, to Col. R. W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 15 Jan 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
          Re: The colt is in fine condition.
        - William H. Tayloe, at Mount Airy, [Richmond County], to Col. Carter, at Richmond, 19 Jan 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - Elizabeth L. Carter, at Washington, to R. W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 25 Jan 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - Elizabeth L. Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 29 Jan 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - Two letters written on one page, Elizabeth Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, and E. V. Lomax, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 1 Feb 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
          Two letters written on one page.
        - Thomas Oldham, Richmond County, Virginia, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 3 Feb 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - Seth Rockwell, at Farnham Church, [Richmond County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 13 Feb 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - Daniel P. Mitchell, at Lancaster Court House, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond City, Virginia, 16 Feb 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
          Re: Whig Party Notice.
        - Henley & Lomax, at Demopolis, [Alabama], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 28 Feb 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
          Re: Going to nominate RWC as Whig candidate.
        - William H. Tayloe, at Mount Airy, [Richmond County], to Col. Carter, at Richmond, 28 Feb 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - John S. Corbin, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, 6 March 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - H. A. Claiborne, Jr., at Richmond, to Col. Robert W. Carter, [at Richmond], 7 March 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - Elizabeth Landon Carter, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond, Virginia, 20 March 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - Benjamin Ogle Tayloe, at Washington, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Warsaw, Virginia, 15 April 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
          Re: Political remarks.
        - Thomas H. Hunton, at Louisville, Westmoreland [County], Virginia, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Richmond County, Virginia, 26 April 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - John Critcher, at Waterview, to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Richmond Court House, Virginia, 29 April 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - Mary B. Carter to Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw Post Office, Richmond County, Virginia, 4 July 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - William W. Forester, at Farnham Church, [Richmond County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, Richmond County, Virginia, 13 July 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - L. Peirce to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Warsaw, Virginia, 17 July 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)
        - Edward T. Tayloe, at Powhatan Hill, [King George County], to Col. Robert W. Carter, at Sabine Hall, near Warsaw, Virginia, 29 July 1843., 1 item. (Folder 31)